linkedin.com/in/KyleTurchik

Kyle Turchik

Full Portfolio: kturchik.github.io

kturchik@sbcglobal.net

(951) 316-1112

Software Engineer

Inspired programmer with 3 years of experience in PC, web, and mobile development emphasizing front-end apps and computer graphics. Proven leader driven by collaboration with multidisciplinary teams. Recognized for being versatile, outgoing, innovative, and delivering quality code that is maintainable, extensible, and well-optimized.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

California State Polytechnic University, Pomona, CA

Cum Laude

Major GPA: **3.6/4.0**

EXPERIENCE

WAREPLAI | R&D Engineer (tiny.cc/arvadalabs)

01/2018 - Present

Implementing core gameplay features for augmented reality games using Unity with Vuforia.

- ♦ Created custom shaders to mask and project objects for seamless AR transition effects.
- ♦ Improved performance and memory efficiency on mobile devices by profiling and optimizing code base.
- ♦ Managed application submission and review process for Google Play and Apple stores.

BLIZZARD ENTERTAINMENT | Software Engineer Intern

06/2017 - 09/2017

Developed a rich single-page web application using WebGL with React and Node.js.

- ♦ Created a 3D rendered display of large real-time data streams from Protocol Buffers over WebSockets.
- ♦ Solved a critical framerate issue, using object pooling and object-oriented patterns with WebGL.
- ♦ Executed detailed UX design and animation specifications with Javascript and CSS.
- ♦ Implemented responsive touch-screen functionality using Hammer.js.
- ♦ Collaborated directly with artists, program managers, and fellow engineers in an Agile/Scrum environment, utilizing JIRA and Confluence to coordinate tasks, Jenkins for CI/CD, and Git for code sharing and reviews.

GOOGLE APPLIED CS PROGRAM | Student Programmer (a.co/appliedcsskills)

04/2016 - 06/2016

Created Android applications with Java and Android Studio as part of a pilot program for a select group of students that reinforces concepts from data structures and algorithms, as well as artificial intelligence.

PROJECTS

Augmented Realms | AR Tabletop Game Simulator (Android/iOS)

12/2017 - Present

♦ Building editing tools for a procedural mesh grid shared live over a multiuser network. (Unity, C#)

inVRasion | VR Multiplayer Game (HTC Vive/PlayStation VR)

09/2017 - Present

♦ Developing UI, AI, weapon physics, and player controls/movement using SteamVR and VRTK. (Unity, C#)

$\textbf{SimpleCraft} \ | \ \textit{Custom Voxel Engine} \ (\textit{PC})$

09/201/

♦ Implemented camera controls, collision detection, and terrain generation using Perlin noise. (OpenGL, Java)

Elemental Fury | VR Multiplayer Game (HTC Vive)

04/2017

- ♦ Implemented combat mechanics, player controls, and client-side network using Photon/PUN. (Unity, C#)
- ♦ Won "3rd Place Overall" at BeachHacks 2017.

Battle of the Bards | Rhythm/RPG Game (PC)

02/2017

- ♦ Created UI, turn-based mechanics, procedural audio, and particle systems. (Unity, C#)
- ♦ Won "2nd Place Overall" and "Best Game Hack" at HackPoly 2017.

LEADERSHIP

Student Game Developer Alliance | Founder, Committee Chair (sada.io)

02/2017 - Present

Founded the largest student-organized game development association in California, dedicated to facilitating game development for 200+ students from 9 universities by organizing educational events and competitions.

Cal Poly Pomona Game Design & Development Club | President

03/2016 - 06/2017

Lead a new student club focused on enabling students to grow technical and teamwork skills through game development, mentoring 60+ members and coordinating large studio-like teams of multidisciplinary students.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C# ♦ C++ ♦ Java ♦ JavaScript ♦ Python ♦ HTML/CSS

Tools: Unity ♦ GIT ♦ OpenGL/DirectX ♦ Visual Studio ♦ WPF/WinForms ♦ .NET ♦ React ♦ Android Studio Concepts: 3D Graphics/Math ♦ UI Implementation (MVVM) ♦ Mobile (Android/iOS) ♦ AR/VR ♦ Agile/Scrum

♦ Object-Oriented Patterns ♦ Memory Management ♦ Computer Networks ♦ Debug Testing/Profiling